《太空堡垒卡拉狄加》前情概要
NARRATOR: Previously on Battlestar Galactica.
李  你不能死!  你必须活下来!
Lee, you can't leave. You have to stay.
你一定要活下来!
You have to really stay.
你必须离开罗丝琳  参加下届总统竞选
GINA: You must betray Roslin and run for President in the upcoming election.
我知道这很困难  但这是唯一的办法
I know it's hard, but it's the only way.
菲斯克被杀一事在整个舰队闹的沸沸扬扬
Word of Fisk's murder has spread out through the entire fleet.
船员会因为失去指挥官而陷入混乱
TIGH: A crew can fall apart when their commander's killed.
帕伽索斯在几周内失去了两个指挥官
Pegasus lost two in a matter of weeks.
我让加纳来指挥
I'm putting Garner in command.
他是个工程师  不是指挥官
But he's an engineer, not a command officer.
他们没有更好的人选了
He's the best they got.
帕伽索斯  巴斯特
Pegasus, Buster.
雷达拦截训练机启程
Dradis intercept training birds are away.
巴斯特  帕伽索斯  收到  前往指定位置
HOSHI: Buster, Pegasus. Roger that. Take station as briefed.
注意通讯将偶尔受到…
Be advised communications will suffer
星际电磁干扰    收到
sporadic interruptions due to stellar EMI activity, acknowledge.
帕伽索斯  巴斯特  收到   通讯太差!
BUSTER: Pegasus, Buster. Acknowledge. Our communications suck.
一直都会这么差吗?
It's gonna be like this all day?
很长时间
Big time.
电磁干扰太强  雷达几乎无法工作
Those binaries are putting out so much EMI, even the dradis is barely working.
好吧  我离开舰队远点
Well, I'm gonna put a little distance between us and the fleet.
离开强干扰区    看看是否能让雷达得到更清晰的图像
Get us out of this soup, see if we can get a cleaner dradis picture.
嗨!
Hey!
不管谁在里面  时间到了! 走吧  快点!
Whoever's in there, time's up! Let's go! Come on!
我们这些疲劳的飞行员要睡觉了
Got a couple of tired Viper jockeys out here who want to sleep.
先去洗澡吧  达克!
Go hit the showers, Duck.
你们洗完回来我们就走了
We'll be gone by the time you get back.
感觉怎么样?
How you feel?
不太好
Oh, not great.
但是卡托医生说我恢复得不错
But Cottle's given me the thumbs-up,
而且已经快一个月了  是时候回去工作了
and it's been almost a month, so I guess it's back to work.
你准备好去"野兽"的肚子里了?
So you ready to go into the belly of The Beast?
"野兽"?        对啊
The Beast? Yeah.
他们现在这么称呼帕伽索斯
That's what they call the Pegasus now.
卡拉狄加叫"木桶"
Galactica's The Bucket.
"木桶"与"野兽"?
The Bucket and The Beast.
嗯
Huh.
我们真是天生的一对
Don't we make a pair?
好啦
Come on.
不  来吧
No, you come on.
来吧
Come on, come on, go.
反正这只是临时任命
Anyway, it's only a temporary assignment.
几周内我就会回来
I should be back again in a couple of weeks.
为什么老头子叫你去呢?
Why'd the old man pick you?
因为星芭儿
One word, Starbuck.
她又搞出什么乱子来了?
Is she in hack again?
还没有
Not yet.
但很明显  自从她接手"野兽"上的飞行训练以来
But apparently she's been driving Commander Garner
已经把加纳指挥官搞得焦头烂额了
up one bulkhead and down the other ever since she took over flight training on,
你叫它什么？    野兽
what did you call it? The Beast.
正好这段时间我不用去飞
And since I won't be flying combat for a while, I...
哦
APOLLO: Oh.
你会提到这个吗?
Were you gonna mention these?
哦  是的  被提升为少校了
Oh, yeah. I got promoted to Major.
你好像并不太高兴
Well, don't sound so happy.
没什么多大意义
Doesn't mean much.
我觉得很有意义
I think it means a lot.
既然你这么说  肯定是的
Oh, well, if you say so, then it must be true.
怎么了?
TYROL: So what's going on?
我们在卸货的时候一个箱子滑落了
We were unloading one of the containers and then one of the crates shifted.
我们看到里面有东西在移动
So we looked inside and we saw that something was moving.
上报过了吗?
Did you call it in?
是的  我们关了门   陆战队正在赶过来
Yeah. We shut the door and the Marines are on their way.
把你的手电给我
Give me a light.
头  我们不知道里面到底是什么
Chief, we don't know what we're dealing with here.
你不觉得我们该等等?
Don't you think we should wait?
等在外面
Just wait out here.
头!
Chief?
这里是卡拉狄加吗?
Is this the Galactica?
是的
Yeah.
你是卡托医生吗?
Are you Doctor Cottle?
怎么回事?
What the hell was that?
我不知道  我们该上报
I don't know. We should call it in.
我打开空间跳跃引擎以防万一
I'm gonna spin up the FTL drive just in case.
帕伽索斯  这里是718号运输机
LYLA: Pegasus, this is Raptor 718.
再说一遍  夏克
Say again, Shark.
夏克  再说一遍   是否遇到紧急情况?
Shark, repeat your last. Did you declare an emergency?
巴斯特  夏克  听到没有?
Buster, Shark, do you read?
夏克  再说一遍   是否遇到紧急情况?
Shark, repeat your last. Did you declare an emergency?
加纳指挥官到
OFFICER: Commander Garner on deck.
巴斯特  夏克  听到没有?
Buster, Shark, do you read?
怎么回事  星先生?
What have you got, Mr. Hoshi?
我无法肯定  长官
Not sure, sir.
应该是巴斯特和夏克遇到紧急情况
I think Buster and Shark are declaring an emergency,
但是听不清楚
but their transmission's garbled.
我们失去了和他们的联系  长官
We've lost them, sir.
我想该再检查一下
OFFICER 1: I want us to recheck that.
好 我需要看看是否是显示错误
OFFICER 2: Okay, I need to check if we're getting some readouts on the problem.
好 我要重新检查了
Yeah? All right, I'll check again.
欢迎  少校
Welcome aboard, Major.
没想到有人来欢迎我
I didn't expect a welcoming committee.
别自作多情了  我只是正好在附近
Don't flatter yourself. I was in the neighborhood.
阿达玛少校来了  长官
Major Adama, sir.
阿达玛少校
Major Adama.
加纳指挥官
Commander Garner.
很高兴见到你  少校   但我不希望是在这种情况下
Glad to see you, Major, although I wish it was under better circumstances.
我们刚刚失去了和两艘正在 执行训练任务的猛禽的联系
We have just lost contact with two of our Raptors out on a training mission.
什么? 什么时候的事?
What? When did that happen?
特蕾丝上尉  如果你认真了履行甲板训练官的职责
Captain Thrace, perhaps if you were actually down on the flight deck
这都是你该做的
and monitoring your Raptors, the way any training officer worth a damn would have done,
你就会知道我们有4个飞行员失踪了
you would know that four of our pilots were missing.
少校
Major.
你跟我来  少校
You with me, Major?
是  长官
Yes, sir.
他们大约一小时前在雷达上消失 他们失踪了
They disappeared from the dradis about an hour ago. They're gone.
都他妈闭嘴!
Shut the hell up!
我们在训练任务中失去两架猛禽
We lose two Raptors in a training mission,
而我居然在指挥官训斥我时才知道
and I only find out when the Commander throws it in my face?
不想说点什么吗?
Don't all speak at once.
长官 有命令要求我们不得和帕伽索斯船员外的…
Sir, it's been made clear that discussing flight deck situations
任何人讨论飞行甲板上的情况
with anyone outside Pegasus crew is not allowed.
对不起  长官
Sorry, sir.
这他妈是谁的好主意?
And whose frakking bright idea was that?
是加纳  对吗?
It was Garner, wasn't it?
这肯定是他的主意
STARBUCK: Of course it was.
这么无能而又多疑
So barely competent and paranoid.
哼
Huh.
居然会集中到一个人身上
There's a hell of a combination.
我有个麻烦
I've a problem.
麻烦的名字就叫卡拉   特蕾丝
That problem's name is Kara Thrace.
我知道怎么和她打交道  长官
I know how to handle her, sir.
并且根据以往记录  她是个非常好的飞行员
And for the record, she is one hell of a Viper pilot.
什么? 你的意思是因为她是个好飞行员
What, I should cut her some slack because she's good in the cockpit,
我就要原谅她的错误?
is that what you're saying?
没人会原谅我们在引擎室犯错
Because nobody ever cut us any slack in the engine room.
我可以明确告诉你这点
I can tell you that right now.
但是可能当个机修工和当个战斗机飞行员是不同的
But then, I don't know maybe being a snipe is different than being a Viper jockey
我们没机会做那些惊险动作
No flashy stunts for us.
没机会在那里卖弄飞行技巧
No flying by the seat of our pants down there.
引擎室就象一块被调整的很好的手表
The engine room is like a finely-tuned watch,
所有的东西都需要被一种非常精确的方式…
and everything in it needs to be monitored and maintained
监控和维护着
in a very precise fashion.
没人可以随意行动
Nobody freelances.
所有事都要以正确的方式   在正确的时间
Everything is done in the proper way, at the proper time,
以正确的顺序完成
in the proper order.
否则就不会有电 不会有灯光
Or there'd be no power, no lights,
你们这些飞行员也不会有热水澡洗
no hot showers for your flyboys.
知道吗  少校  我认为这里有些人
You know, Major, I think some of the people around here
可以从机修工身上学到点东西
could learn a thing or two from the snipes.
对不起  总统女士    但是时间到了
I'm sorry, Madam President, but it's that time.
哦
Oh.
竞选见面会
The campaign meeting.
我们已经把它推迟了好几周
Mmm-hmm. You've been putting it off for weeks.
总统竞选就要开始了
And we do have a presidential election coming up,
除非你决定不再连任
unless you've decided not to run.
老实对你说 特瑞
I'm gonna be perfectly honest with you, Tory.
有几次我是不想干了
I've thought about it a few times,
但现在我还是在这里
but, no, I'm still here.
有太多事要做 所以…
There's so much to do, so
我们来谈谈政治吧
let's talk politics.
好极了
Great.
这是整个舰队第一次民意测验的结果
Here are the results from our first fleet-wide poll.
你是怎么做到的?
How did you manage this?
我在戴尔菲做了五年的…
I was precinct captain for the Federalist Party
联邦党选区负责人
in Delphi for five years.
那时我们做民意测验  看看市长应该在午餐时吃什么
We did polls to see what the mayor should have for lunch.
因为各方面的帮助  你已经开了个好头
For what it's worth, you've managed to walk a very fine line.
你的竞选既有军方的支持
Your presidential bid has the support of
又有平民舰队的支持
both the military and the civilian fleet,
而且吉米尼的宗教领袖
and you've received enthusiastic endorsements
也狂热地支持你
from the Gemenese religious leaders.
这在你的对手是个判过刑的恐怖分子的时候很有用
Well, it helps when your only real rival is a convicted terrorist.
我有能力领导这支舰队吗?
Am I capable of leading this fleet?
绝对
Absolutely.
而且曾经我有过这样的机会
And for a time, I almost had a chance,
直到罗拉·罗丝琳从一个政客变成了一个先知
until Laura Roslin ascended from politician to prophet.
老实说我赢不了
The truth is, I can't win.
但是你也许可以
But you could.
你在奉承我 扎拉克先生
You flatter me, Mr. Zarek, really,
但我不确定是否参与竞选
but I'm not sure I'm cut out for a life in politics,
因为我发现做副总统非常的无趣
as I find the vice-presidency and everything to do with it very tedious.
我能想象帮助罗丝琳是件很累的事
I would imagine carrying water for Roslin would get old after a time,
但是你在政府中的地位使你成为完美的候选人 博士
but it's the office that makes you the perfect candidate, Doctor.
你很受欢迎
You're pre-sold.
真的?
Really?
谁?
To whom?
你会感到惊奇  有多少人渴望冰冷的科学
You'd be surprised how many people crave the assurances of cold science
而不是吉米尼人那些迷信的胡说
as opposed to the superstitious ravings of the Gemenese.
作为一个科学家  你代表着希望
As a scientist, you offer hope.
考虑一下吧
Think about it.
而你  汤姆
And you, Tom?
你会就这么退出? 你能吗?
You'll just step aside, will you?
我会很高兴支持一个有真正信念的人
I'm just happy to back a man of true conviction.
一个不忘记自己朋友的人
A man who remembers his friends.
全体注意
CASE: Attention on deck.
稍息
APOLLO: At ease.
斯丁格到哪儿去了?
Where's Stinger?
他说错了话  惹恼了加纳
He's in hack for mouthing off to Garner.
给关了禁闭
Stepped on his precious little toes.
混蛋加纳
Frakking Garner.
他真是个白痴
STARBUCK: He's such an idiot. He's just...
好了  都住嘴!
All right, lock that up!
都搞搞清楚
Get something straight.
两艘失踪的猛禽上的飞行员 将在36小时内缺氧
We got two missing Raptor crews who are gonna be out of oxygen in 36 hours.
这才是我们该关心的
That's all that matters.
所以  所有人都停止胡扯  开始你们的工作
So everyone knock off the schoolyard crap and start doing your frakking jobs.
现在  不要再斤斤计较
Now, we need to start thinking outside the box.
这样才能干好工作
Which is supposed to be what you do best.
对不起  少校
Sorry, Major.
好了
All right.
我想知道关于
I wanna know everything there is to know
失踪运输机和飞行员的一切情况
about these missing Raptors and their crews.
人员信息 战机情况 通讯记录
I wanna know personal quirks, aircraft squawks, wireless transmissions,
任何可能有帮助的东西
anything that might help.
好  开始干活吧
Good. Get to it.
她怎么样?
How is she?
莱雅有四个月身孕  但她不想要这个孩子
Rya's four months pregnant and doesn't wanna be.
我知道吉米尼人反对女人堕胎
I understand the Gemenese have a problem with women terminating their pregnancies.
泰罗说她指名道姓要见你
Tyrol said that she asked for you by name.
你能告诉我到底为什么吗?
Do you want to tell me what that's really all about?
实话实说  我得到消息有个女孩要来
Pretty straightforward, really. I get a note that a girl is on the way,
她来了  我干我该干的  然后她离开
she arrives, I do my work, and she leaves.
我不会问些不该问的问题
I don't ask a lot of questions.
你要开始问了
You're gonna start.
我想和她谈谈
I wanna talk to her.
我是阿达玛上将
I'm Admiral Adama.
别担心  我只是来和你谈谈
Don't worry, I've just come to talk.
不管你怎么说  我都不会改变主意
It doesn't matter what you say. I'm not gonna change my mind.
你父母有点担心你
Your parents are a little worried about you.
他们已经通过吉米尼议员和我联系过了
They've contacted me through the Gemenon representative.
我父母?
My parents?
天啊
Oh, gods.
你知道他们会怎么对我吗?
Do you have any idea what they would do to me?
求你  别把我送回去
Please, do not send me back.
你是个偷渡者   这是一艘军舰
You're a stowaway aboard a military ship.
可以说她是个政治迫害的受害者
COTTLE: Some people might say she was a victim of political persecution.
她可以申请政治避难
Hell, she could apply for asylum.
政治避难
Asylum.
就是的  我想要政治避难
That's it. I want asylum.
根据吉米尼法律  这个女孩依然是她父母的财产
Under Gemenon law, the girl is still the property of her parents,
等女孩安全回去后他们会处理她
and they can deal with her once she's safely back on her ship.
老实说  我更关心…
To be honest, I'm more concerned
由此事造成的影响
with the broader implications of this matter.
莎拉
Sarah.
我知道你不想听这个
I know you don't wanna hear this,
但是我的人民 我的选民们要求对此事采取行动
but my people, my voters, are demanding action on this issue.
我们已经说过
We have been through this.
堕胎在赛昂人攻击前是合法的
Abortion was legal under Colonial law before the attacks,
所以现在依然合法
and so it is still legal today.
这是侮辱神灵
It's obscene.
圣经载明堕胎是众神厌恶之事
The scriptures view abortion as an abomination in the eyes of the gods.
如果你想在未来竞选中得到我们的支持
You cannot equivocate on this point
你就得处理这个问题
if you want our support in the coming election.
莱雅·基比的政治避难申请正在等待审批
Rya Kibby's petition for asylum is under review.
谢谢  莎拉  非常感谢你能过来
Thank you, Sarah, very much, for coming in.
我不会交出那个女孩  我也不会禁止堕胎
I'm not turning that girl over. I'm certainly not banning abortion.
那就这样
TORY: Then don't.
但是我们必须尽快处理这件事
But we have to move aggressively on this thing.
我会安排一个你和法人团的电话会议
I'm gonna arrange a conference call with you and the Quorum,
否则可能会搞的不可收拾
or this is gonna get out of hand, fast.
她可和比利不一样啊
She's not Billy.
是的
No, she's not.
怎么了?
What?
我不想说
I hate to say this
...因为这是个政治问题
because I know that this is a political issue.
...事实是  那个数字上升得太慢
The fact is, that number doesn't go up very often.
我的整个职业生涯就在为女性自身权利而斗争
I have fought for a woman's right to control her body my entire career.
不
No.
我只是想起了你在赛昂人攻击后所说的
I'm just remembering what you said right after the Cylon attack.
你说如果我们真想拯救人类
That if we really wanna save the human race,
我们最好开始生儿育女
we better start having babies.
没有  没有  什么都没有
Nothing, nothing, and more nothing.
夏克最后的通话记录在哪里?
Where is Shark's last transmission?
不是很多
Well, there's not much there.
收…求救…方位…失事
"Eve, distress, bearing, wreck,
…是…紧急…收到
"shuns, emerge, read. "
他们在求救
They're in distress.
他们给出了方位指示
They give a bearing requesting instructions,
"这是紧急事件 能收到吗？"
"It's an emergency. Can you read?"
可能  但是这个"收"是什么意思?
Maybe. But what's this "eve" fragment here?
“收…求救”   “收…求救”
"Eve, distress. " "Eve, distress. "
"求救信号"
Distress call.
"收...收到"?
Eve. Receive... Received.
"收到求救信号"
Received distress call.
好吧  谁在求救?
Okay. From who?
我不知道
I don't know.
但也许他们就是去看看发生了什么
But maybe that's where they went, to go find out.
指挥官  特蕾丝上尉对于失踪的猛禽有个想法
APOLLO: Commander, Captain Thrace has a theory about our missing Raptors, sir.
很好  因为她搞丢了他们
That's good, considering she lost them.
什么意思?
Excuse me?
他们不是在执行你那个所谓的训练任务吗?
Well, they were out on one of your so-called training missions,
难道不是吗? 上尉
weren't they, Captain?
我所谓的训练任务?
My "so-called" training missions.
大家放松些
Okay, let's just take this easy.
在你没有豪饮或者挑动兵变之余
That's when you're not boozing or sowing mutiny amongst the crew.
兵变?
Mutiny.
指挥官  我们应该在没人的地方讨论这些
Commander, we should take this to a private place.
你以为我不知道在我的船上发生了些什么?
Don't you think I know what's happening on my own ship?
"无能而又多疑"?
"Barely competent and paranoid. "
那都是私下说说的    准确地说
That was off the record. I was just venting.
我只是在发泄
Accurately.
我要把你送上军事法庭
I'll have you court-martialed.
指挥官  我不是在为特蕾丝上尉的行为辩护
Commander, I'm not defending Captain Thrace's behavior...
谢谢  少校
Thanks, Major.
特蕾丝上尉  你现在被限制行动了
Captain Thrace, you're restricted to quarters
直到我把你送回卡拉狄加
until I can ship you back to Galactica.
你是阿达玛的宠物  让他处理你
You're Adama's pet. Let him deal with you.
少校？
Major?
是  长官
Sir.
你才上舰四天不到就已经面临指控
You've been onboard less than four days and you're already facing charges.
你还真是不浪费任何时间  是吗?
You don't waste any time, do you?
你不也是  李
Neither do you, Lee.
做加纳的新玩伴  感觉如何?
How's it feel being Garner's new playmate?
我是来这里工作的
I'm here to do a job.
是啊  要把喜欢大声嚷嚷不听话的卡拉·特蕾丝搞定
Yeah, keep a loudmouth, disobedient, frak-up Kara Thrace in line.
你工作的并不出色 对吧?
Not doing such a good job, are you?
显然是的
Evidently not.
我们时间不多  那些失踪飞行员的氧气就要用尽了
We don't have much time, those guys are running out of air.
是  我努力过了  知道吗?
Yeah, well, I tried, all right?
自从我来帕伽索斯  一直在努力和帮忙
All I have done since I got to The Beast is try and help,
而我所得到的就是这个下场
and all I've gotten is Garner's foot in my ass.
也许你就应该得到这个下场
Well, maybe you need a kick in the ass!
好吧
All right.
终于入正题了
Here we go, finally.
你到底有什么问题?
What is your problem, anyway?
我的问题?
What's my problem? What's my problem?
卡拉 我的问题就是你 你总是把事情搞砸
Well, Kara, my problem is you. You keep frakking up,
而我总是来给你收拾
and I keep having to clean it up,
我累了
and I am officially sick of it.
可怜的李  你生活的如此辛苦  是不是?
Poor Lee, your life is so hard, isn't it?
你的意思是  自从我给打中了之后?
You mean since I got shot?
你要不要听我认为巴斯特他们出了什么事
You wanna hear what I think happened to Buster or not?
帕伽索斯  红魔    我已经接近了…
Pegasus, Red Devil. I'm nearing the last coordinates
猛禽失踪前最后的坐标
where our Raptors went missing.
重复 紧…
SHARK:Repeat, emer...
有…
There are...
巴斯特  是你吗?
RED DEVIL: Buster, is that you?
我是红魔 是你吗? 伙计 回话
This is Red Devil, man. Is that you, buddy? Come back to me.
电力系统故障  氧气快要用完了
SHARK:Out of power. Oxygen almost out.
帮帮我们
By the gods, help!
长官  一架搜索机在巴斯特失去联系的地点附近
Sir, one of our search Raptors just picked a possible distress signal
接收到可能是呼救的信号
from near where Pegasus lost communications with Buster's ship.
终于有点消息了
Finally.
可能是呼救信号
A possible distress signal.
还有个想法 可能是巴斯特
There's a theory that Buster himself might have jumped away
去追踪一个假的呼救信号 那可能是个陷阱
to run down a phony distress call. It could be a trap.
想法? 是你的想法吗  少校?
A theory? Is this your theory, Major?
这是特蕾丝上尉的想法吧  不是吗?
This is Captain Thrace's theory, is it not?
索伦顿先生 你能帮我们确定那个求救信号来自那里吗
Mr. Thornton, can you give us a fix on where this distress signal is coming from?
是  长官  在很远  超过40 SU
Yes, sir, it's long range, over 40 SU away.
那就预热空间跳跃引擎  准备跳跃
Then spin up the FTL drive and prepare to jump the ship.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
长官  这并不仅仅是特蕾丝上尉的想法
Sir, this isn't just Captain Thrace's theory.
我也认为这是赛昂人设的陷阱  而且
I think this is a Cylon trap, and...
而且我不同意
And I disagree.
现在给我接通阿达玛上将
Now get Admiral Adama on the line.
我要去救我们的人了
I'm going to get our men.
上将  我们终于找到
Admiral, we've finally got the break we've been looking for,
求救信号了
a bearing on the distress signal.
我可以在两分钟内跳跃到那里
I can jump there inside of two minutes.
指挥官  相信我  我理解你的感受
Commander, believe me, I understand how you feel.
但是赛昂人知道如何把我们引入陷阱
The Cylons have been known to lure our ships into traps
使用假的求救信号
using fake distress calls.
你考虑过这点吗?
Have you considered that?
我们考虑过了  长官   但我们觉得不太可能
We have, sir. It's a scenario we don't think likely.
我们?
We?
阿达玛少校  你同意吗?
Major Adama, do you concur?
长官
Sir,
特蕾丝上尉和我都认为 前面两艘猛禽
Captain Thrace and I are of the opinion that the first two Raptors
很有可能就是这样落入了陷阱
may very well have been lured away by just such a trick.
我不同意这种观点
An opinion I do not share, sir.
全副武装去侦查一下
We'll send a recon mission in full force.
五架猛禽
Five Raptors.
三架护航 两架救援
Three escort, two rescue.
照我的命令做  指挥官
You have your orders, Commander.
是  长官    谢谢  长官
Yes, sir. Thank you, sir.
谢谢  少校
Thank you, Major.
我相信别处会需要你的专家意见
I'm sure your expertise is needed elsewhere.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
是的  我有点好奇
Yes, I am curious.
为什么突然对人口统计学感兴趣了
Why the sudden interest in the fleet's demographic projections?
有迹象表明我们的政府内部不和
An issue has emerged that may prove divisive to our administration.
我想在做决定前掌握所有的实际情况
I would like all the facts in hand before making my decision.
现在又成了我们的政府?
So now it's our administration.
她肯定是急了
She must be desperate.
好吧  我很忙
Well, I'm a very busy man.
幸运的是  我在7个月前作了初步的计算
Luckily, I made an initial calculation on these figures over seven months ago
那时候好像没人对这个感兴趣
when nobody seemed interested or concerned.
我要做的就是把帕伽索斯船员的因素加入
All I had to do was factor in the numbers from the Pegasus crew.
用不了我多少时间
It took me hardly any time at all and I didn't mind.
看  我我帮你省了很多麻烦
Look, I'll save you the bother. You needn't read the report.
如果我们继续现在的情况
If we continue on our present course,
人类将在18年内灭绝
within the next 18 years, the human race will simply be extinct.
自从接任总统以来我就把维护受攻击前…
ROSLIN:Since assuming the Presidency, I've made it my mission to maintain
我们所享受的人权和自由作为我的任务
the rights and freedoms we so enjoyed prior to the attack.
其中一项权利现在已经…
One of these rights has now come into direct conflict
和人类的生存直接抵触
with the survival of the species.
我发现我必须做出一个非常困难的决定
And I find myself forced to make a very difficult decision.
这个问题非常明显
The issue is stark.
如果人类文明想要继续生存
The fact is that if this civilization is to survive, we must,
我们必须增加舰队人口
must repopulate this fleet.
因此  我将签发一项行政命令
Therefore, I am issuing an executive order.
从今天开始
From this day forward,
任何人妨碍孩子的出生
anyone seeking to interfere with the birth of a child,
不管是母亲
whether it be the mother
或者开业医师
or a medical practitioner,
均将视为犯罪并处刑
shall be subject to criminal penalty.
谢谢
Thank you.
所有飞行甲板人员  请去各部报到
OFFICER:All flight deck personnel, please report to stations.
好了  快点  我们走  我们走
CASE: All right, come on. Let's go! Let's go!
凯丝上尉  怎么了?
Captain Case, what's going on?
我们接到命令  一级戒备
We've been ordered to scramble, condition one.
帕伽索斯正准备跳跃 我们将从另一面发射出去
Ship's getting ready to jump, we're gonna launch on the other side.
去机库!
Get down to the hangar deck.
什么?
What?
你是我们最好的飞行员   所以快去机库  找一架蝮蛇
Look, you're the best pilot we've got, so get down there, and find a Viper.
你早该承认这一点了
It's about time you admit that!
指挥官  怎么了?
Commander, what's our sitrep?
这是一项营救任务  少校
This is a rescue mission, Major.
谁授权的?
On whose authority?
我  我要把我的飞行员带回家
Mine. I'm bringing my pilots home.
恕我直言长官  如果这是赛昂人设下的陷阱
All due respect, sir, but if this is a Cylon trap,
那我们就栽进去了  我们应该先派人武装侦查
then we are entering blind. We should send a force recon...
我的飞行员就要死了  少校!  没空侦查了
My pilots are dying down there, Major. I'm going in. I'm not waiting on recon.
指挥官  你违反了上将的命令
Commander, this is in direct violation of the Admiral's orders.
少校  离开这里
Major, leave combat...
这是抗命行为
Making this an illegal action on your part, sir.
你被解职了  少校
You are relieved, Major.
卫兵
Sergeant of the Guard.
我被迫接管本舰…
I am forced to take command of this vessel...
这个人违背命令
This man is in direct disobedience of an order...
…根据联邦法律  我要求逮捕此人
...under federal regulations and place you under arrest.
军士  把他带下去
Sergeant, take him below.
军士  指挥官已被解职  把他护送到他的住处去
Sergeant, the Commander has been properly relieved. Escort him to his quarters.
这个人并非本舰船员   而你…
This man is not a member of this crew, and you will obey
必须服从我的命令  现在就执行
a direct order that you have been given by me, and you will do it now.
少校  你跟我走
Major, if you'll come with me.
上将  帕伽索斯跳走了  他们消失了
Admiral, the Pegasus has jumped. They're gone.
雷达信号清晰  跳跃未受任何干扰
Dradis signal's clean. Jump put us clear of any interference.
雷达显示两架猛禽
Sir, I show two Raptors.
识别信号匹配  是我们的人
Transponder codes match. They're ours.
星先生   告诉空军指挥官派出救援队
Mr. Hoshi, tell the CAG to launch our recovery team,
把我们的人带回来
and let's bring our people home.
是  长官
Aye, sir.
帕伽索斯  我是红魔   猛禽看上去完好
Pegasus, Red Devil. Our two birds look intact.
还无法看清内部
I can't quite see inside yet.
指挥官  我们无法通过无线控制猛禽
Commander, we're unable to raise the Raptors on wireless.
帕伽索斯  两架猛禽的飞行员都死了
Pegasus, both Raptor crews are dead.
我再说一遍  他们都死了
I repeat, they're all dead.
长官  三艘赛昂基地船跳入武器射程
Sir, three Cylon Baseships just jumped into weapons range.
哦  我的天哪
Oh, my gods.
他们发射了核弹  做好受到冲击的准备
They're launching nukes! Brace for impact!
损失报告?
Damage report.
两个核弹在尾部爆炸  长官
Two... Two nuclear detonations in the stern, sir.
空间跳跃引擎失效  长官
FTL drive inoperative, sir.
我们陷在这里了  长官
We're stuck here, sir.
好了  修博特  你带着红色中队  从右边攻击他
All right, Showboat, you take Red Squadron, hit them on the right.
凯特博得  你带着绿色中队从左边攻击 余下的人跟着我
Catbird, you take Green, hit them on the left. The rest of you, follow me.
我们去攻击中部
We're going straight up the gut.
军士  我想你有更重要的事去做
Sergeant, I think you have better things to do.
哦  那么转子是好的?
Well, then the spinner's fine.
肯定是传感器 只要拔出来
It's gotta be a sensor. Just pull it.
不 不 听我说 听我说 只要拔出来
No, no. Listen to me. Listen to me. Just pull it. Pull it!
核爆炸
Nuclear detonation.
顶部热交换器结构性损坏
There's structural damage along the topside heat exchanger.
象这样我们顶不了多久   空间跳跃引擎还要多久可以修好?
They can't take much more of this, how long before those drives are back up?
我不知道  他们好像听不懂我说的
I don't know. They don't seem to understand.
我必须亲自下去
I need to go down there.
你来指挥
You have the con.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
由我指挥
I have the con.
攻击离我们最近的基地船
Make for the nearest Baseship,
把船身反转使我们的顶部避开他们的火力线
and roll us over to keep our topside out of their line of fire.
星  联络星芭儿和凯斯
Hoshi, contact Starbuck and Case.
告诉他们我接手指挥
Tell them I've assumed command
让他们全力以赴保护我们的顶部
and to concentrate on protecting our topside.
是  长官
Aye, sir.
维尔寇  帕伽索斯   我们在你后面
Wilco, Pegasus. We got your back.
盖塔先生  能联络上吗?
Mr. Gaeta, any contact?
不行  长官
Negative, sir.
给我
Give me this.
我能穿过去吗?
Can I get through there?
基地船在正前方  我们正在迅速接近
Baseship dead ahead. We're closing rapidly.
我们无法继续承受这样的打击  少校
We can't keep taking hits like this, Major.
舵手  保持方向
Helm, steady as you go.
船头的舰炮准备齐射
Have the bow batteries stand by for salvo fire.
目标是他们的中轴
Target their center axis.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
如果我们如果不能扭转劣势
See if we can't cut down the odds.
我们需要马上修复空间跳跃引擎 否则我们死定了
We need those FTLs fixed soon or we're dead.
2200  主炮可以发射
Twenty-two hundred. Main battery has a firing solution.
那就发射吧
Fire.
我办不到 长官
CREWMAN: I wouldn't try it without a canteen, sir.
冷冻剂压力低于表值 主进口被阻塞
GARNER: Coolant pressure's off-scale low. Primary inlet's choked.
压力在降低  我们必须堵住里面的裂口
The pressure's dropping. We've got a hull breach in there somewhere.
我们必须进去  打开辅助阀门
Well, we gotta get in there and open the auxiliary valve.
我们不能那么做  长官
We can't do that, sir.
我们必须这么做
We have to!
长官  那个裂口会把里面所有的氧气泄漏掉
Sir, that breach could vent all our oxygen into space!
我们没有选择余地了    打开舱门
We don't have a choice. Now open the hatch!
呼吸装置?
Breathing gear?
救火的时候都用光了  长官
We used it all in fighting the fire, sir.
给我一把榔头和一把12号螺丝起子
Give me a sledge and a number 12 spanner.
好了
Okay.
现在关掉我身后的舱门  氧气在流失
Now, close this hatch behind me. We're losing air.
关掉这个他妈的舱门  关掉
Close the goddamn hatch! Close it!
基地船正在转向
The Baseship's turning away. He's...
他要逃跑  少校
He's frakking running, Major!
但是其他两艘可没逃
But the other two aren't.
他们来势很猛
They're coming hard.
舵手 左满舵
Helm, left full.
我找到了备份系统
I'm at the manifold.
我看看能不能转动他们
I'm gonna see if I can turn them.
的确有气体泄漏
There's definitely air escaping
在SVC转发器上有一个裂缝
through a crack over the FCC relay.
裂痕在后面
Your breach is behind that.
星芭儿报告弹药用尽  少校
Starbuck reports Vipers are skosh ammo, Major.
他们下去对这些杂种发射火箭弹了
They're down to throwing rocks at the bastards.
我们必须马上离开这里  长官
We've got to haul ass outta here now, sir. Sir!
小心 右侧
PILOT: Watch yourself, starboard side!
快点  加纳
Come on, Garner.
氧气指示已经到红色区域  队长   你就快缺氧了
BELLAMY: O2's in the red, Skipper. You're almost out of air.
你成功了  压力回升了
You got it! The pressure's coming back up!
现在快出来  快点
Now get the frak outta there! Come on!
你没氧气了  队长  快出来  队长?
Air's gone, Skipper. Get out of there. Skipper!
工程人员报告空间跳跃引擎修复并且已经准备好
Engineering reporting a green board, FTL drive online and ready.
好吧  进行跳跃准备
Okay, commence jump prep.
把战机都叫回来
Bring our birds home.
帕伽索斯  星芭儿  我后面除了赛昂没别人了
Pegasus, Starbuck. Nobody behind me but toasters.
现在带我们离开这里
Now, get us out of here!
战斗机都返航了    降落区闸门已经关闭
Air wing's back on board. Launch bays secure.
跳跃
Jump.
你给了加纳很多赞誉
You give Garner a lot of credit.
都是真的
Well, it's all true.
他献出生命来拯救帕伽索斯
He gave his life to save the ship.
星芭儿的报告可没那么客气了
Starbuck's report wasn't so kind.
她有她的观点
Well, she had her perspective
而我有我的
and I had mine.
你认为  这个不作记录
In your opinion, off the record,
加纳的缺点是什么?
what was Garner's flaw?
他过去习惯于和机器一起工作
He was used to working with machines.
而指挥官却是和人打交道
Command is about people.
记住这点
Remember that
我要你来指挥"野兽"
as you take command of The Beast.
任命加纳是我的决定
Garner was my decision.
他的失败是我的责任
His failure's my responsibility.
不要让我再犯一次错
Don't let me fail a second time.
恭喜你  指挥官
Congratulations, Commander.
总统女士  有谣言说你不打算起诉…
Madam President, word has it that you do not intend
那个在卡拉狄加上的吉米尼女孩
to prosecute the Gemenese girl on Galactica.
她有名字  莎拉
She has a name, Sarah.
我想莱雅已经受够了苦
And I think that Rya has suffered enough.
她刚刚做了堕胎
She's just been through an abortion.
我已经同意让她在卡拉狄加上政治避难
I've granted her asylum aboard Galactica.
这完全违反了法律
This is in total violation of the law.
我的命令在她手术后才发出
My order came after she sought her procedure.
并没有违法
No laws have been broken.
那个女孩应该回家  和父母一起  我坚持
The girl belongs at home with her parents. I insist.
你已经得到了你想要的
You have your pound of flesh,
我建议你带着你的胜利走吧
and I suggest you take your victory and you move on.
好 女士
Ma'am.
你已经有所觉悟了吧
You realize you're screwed, right?
所有的这些压力 责任  失眠
All the pressure, the responsibility, the sleepless nights.
那些军官  你有得苦啦
All the officers giving you a hard time.
是啊  也可能更糟   如果你是我的空军指挥官
Yeah, well, it could be worse. You could be my CAG.
我会留在这里做卡拉狄加的空军指挥官
I'm gonna stay here and be Galactica's CAG.
好像因为有人要时时照看着我
Something about wanting to keep an eye on me.
你和泰上校在早上例会中会有很多乐趣的
Well, you and Colonel Tigh have a lot of fun at those early morning briefings,
因为副长会有很多乐子
'cause the XO's a lot of fun the first thing.
好极了
Great.
恭喜!
Congratulations.
真的
Really.
恭喜!
Congratulations.
你应得的
You deserve it.
我知道我为什么对你发火
I know why I was mad at you, Kara.
一个简单的"谢谢"就够了
A simple thank you would've been sufficient.
因为你一直就是那么做的
Because you were doing what you always did.
顶撞上级  然后拍拍屁股走人
Buck authority and get away with it.
我也干过一次
I bucked authority once,
差点失去了所有的东西
and I almost lost everything.
所以我猜等我去了帕伽索斯
So I guess when I showed up on Pegasus and there you were,
你又会搞出点什么事来
doing it all over again...
我不知道  想想就烦
I don't know. It pissed me off.
只是随便说说  对吧?
Doesn't make a lot of sense, does it?
有时候你应该听听我大脑工作的方式
You should hear the way my brain works sometimes.
我们和好了吧?
Are we okay?
你有大脑?
You have a brain?
总统女士  你把堕胎犯罪化已经激怒了一些人
Madam President, your decision to criminalize abortion has created a furor.
你认为这会影响到你的竞选吗?
Do you think that's hurt your standing in the polls?
绝对会
Absolutely.
请允许我  总统女士
If I may, Madam President.
由于最近的事件
It is true, in the light of recent events,
总统也许会失去某些人的支持
the President may have lost support in some quarters.
我请大家理解   因为这是非常时期
I would ask the people to understand that, if this is an extreme decision,
所以会有非常决定
we live in extreme times.
这个决定的初衷是好的
The decision has been made with good faith.
然而我  凭良心说不支持这个决定
I, however, cannot with good conscience support it.
我很对不起  总统女士
I'm so sorry, Madam President,
赛昂人并不理解自由这个词的含义
but the Cylon have no understanding of the meaning of the word freedom.
他们怎么可能理解? 他们只是被编程的机器而已
How could they? They're programmed machines.
每当你拿走我们的一种自由
Every time you take away one of our freedoms,
每当你限制或者剥夺我们的一项权利
every time we restrict or curtail one of our rights,
我们就一步步变得更象赛昂人
we become one step closer to being like them.
作为副总统  我必须接受这个政府的领导
As the Vice President, I am bound to follow the administration's lead.
作为总统
As President,
我就不会再受此限制
I should have no such strictures.
根据目前情况  我已无可选择
Given the current situation, I'm afraid that I have no alternative
我只能宣布  从现在开始  我参加总统竞选
but to announce that I am, as of now, a candidate for the Presidency.